The Ultimate
(テンテン)ん？
Huh?!
PERSEVERANCE
リーったら
まだあの修業やってたの。
I didn't know Lee kept going
with that training.
《ネジ : 中忍試験中だというのに
呆れたやつだ》
We're in the middle
of the Chunin Exams!
What is he thinking?
(リー)シラ君 僕の本気を見せます。
Shira! I will show
you how serious I am!
(セン)最初に言っとくけど
シラはとんでもなく強いよ。
Let me warn you…
Shira's super strong!
(シラ)は～っ。
僕だって 強くなっています！
I've become strong too!
これが俺にとって 最後の戦い。
This is my last fight.
最後？
Last?
いくぞ リー。
Here I come, Lee!
はぁ～！
何これ とんでもなく速い。
What is this?
Their speed is ridiculous!
剛拳と剛拳の戦い。
A battle of powerful fists…
そうめったに見られるものでは
ないな。
It's not something
you get to see often.
《俺の術を止めたやつだ》
He stopped my jutsu.
((クッ… すべて受けきっただと!?))
He countered every move?!
《できれば俺も
戦ってみたかった》
If I could, I would have liked
to fight him too.
Amazing…
《さすがです。
これだけ強い体術使いは➡
I haven't faced
a taijutsu user this strong
ガイ先生とネジ以来です》
since Guy Sensei and Neji!
《正確な技だ。
一撃一撃に情念を感じる。
He has a fine technique…
I feel his passion in
every punch he throws.
キミが いかに
修業を重ねてきたかが➡
The intensity of his training
comes across clearly.
よく伝わってくる》
うっ。
リー キミには感謝している。
Lee!
I'm grateful to you.
えっ？
俺がこうして
忍としていられるのは➡
Perhaps it's all because of you
that I can be a shinobi.
キミのおかげかもしれない。
あの時 我愛羅様は言った。
Lord Gaara said
this to me back then…
((我愛羅 : 俺は以前 木ノ葉で➡
I once met someone just like you
in Hidden Leaf Village.
お前と同じような者と
出会ったことがある。
その者は たゆまぬ努力で
立派な忍となっている。
Through sheer determination,
he has become a fine shinobi.
(シラ お前なら
その者にも劣らぬ忍となろう))
Shira… I predict you will be
as good a shinobi as he.
キミのこぶしが我愛羅様の気持を
変えたのかもしれない。
It might have been your fists
that changed Lord Gaara.
いいえ 僕は関係ありません。
No, I had nothing to do with that!
それは キミの努力が
我愛羅君に言わせた言葉です。
It was your perseverance
that moved Lord Gaara.
リー その礼は俺の本気で返す！
Lee, I'm going to show you
my gratitude in earnest!
当然です。 それが
体術をきわめる者同士の流儀。
Well said!
That is the creed
of those of us
who are dedicated to
the mastery of taijutsu.
なんかあの２人 楽しそうね。
They seem to be enjoying this.
Maybe Lee has met someone
he can consider a true rival.
リーは今 本当のライバルと思える相手に
出会えたのかもしれない。
一人での修業には限界がある。
You can only go so far
training alone.
その限界を
超えさせてくれるのがライバル。
Having a rival is what
helps you surpass those limits.
へぇ～ ネジにもライバルがいるの？
I see.
Do you have a rival, Neji?
俺のライバル…。
My rival?
((ナルト : 日向の憎しみの運命だか
何だか知んねえがな➡
I don't know what
the Hyuga destiny of hatred is!
お前が無理だっつうなら
もう何もしなくていい！
But if you're going to
say it's futile,
you don't have to do anything!
(俺が火影になってから
日向を変えてやるよ！))
After I become the Hokage…
I'll change the Hyuga!
《俺の相手になるのはお前だけだ。
You're the only one
who can be my rival…
早く帰って来い ナルト》
So hurry up and
come home, Naruto!
まだ２人とも
決定打はないみたいね。
Neither one of them has delivered
a decisive blow yet.
互いに様子を見合っているからな。
They're just sizing
each other up right now.
えっ!? あいつら
まだ本気出してないの？
What?
They're not fighting at
their full potential?
It's more like 50%.
(ネジ)５割程度だろう。
How much can a body endure?
どんだけ体がキレキレなのよ。
このまま互角でいったら…。
If they stay evenly matched like this…
No…
いいや 互角というのは違う。
They're not quite equal.
えっ それも違うの？
Huh? They're not?
技のスピード 手数の多さは
今のところ互角だ。
They're equal in speed and in
the number of moves they have…
だが シラの体格は➡
But Shira's physique is
a full size bigger than Lee's.
リーよりひと回り大きい。
打撃技は体重差で
一打の重みが違ってくる。
In boxing, the difference
in body weight
influences the intensity of the blow.
互角に見えても
体重の少ないリーには…。
While they may look
evenly matched,
Lee with his smaller build…
ダメージがたまってるってこと？
Is sustaining more damage?
リーも そろそろ
それを感じ始めてる頃だろう。
Lee should be feeling
the effects pretty soon.
《シラ君のほうが➡
Blow for blow, Shira's punches
are harder than mine!
一撃 一撃が重い
このままじゃ…》
At this rate…
リー！
Lee!
あの構えは…。
リーのやつ➡
That stance!
Don't tell me Lee plans
to use the Lotus!
蓮華を使うつもりか!?
危険だわ。
It's too dangerous!
ですが 彼は➡
But he is an opponent
who is worth that risk!
それを冒すにふさわしい相手です。
はぁ～！
うぅ…。
おぉ～！
はっ！ うっ。
《バカな 第一開門が開かない。
No way!
The First Gate won't open!
どうして？》
Why?!
僕の点穴を突いて
チャクラの流れを封じたんですね。
You hit my Chakra Points and
stopped the flow of chakra!
(シラ)体術使い同士
長所も短所もわかっている。
As a taijutsu user like you,
I know all your strengths
and weaknesses.
キミが八門遁甲といわれる
秘術を使うこともな。
As well as the fact that you are
versed in the secret jutsu,
the Eight Inner Gates!
うっ。
From now, I mean business!
ここからが 俺の本気だ。
シラのモードが変わった。
Shira switched his mode.
やっと本気を出すのね。
He's getting serious now!
行くぞ リー。
Here I come, Lee!
ぐわっ。
どうしたの？ 急に
攻撃が連続で当たり始めた。
What's happening?!
All of a sudden, his attacks
became relentless and accurate!
This is—!
これは… あっ。
音だ。
音？
The sound!
Sound?!
やつの攻撃から音が消えている。
His attacks are silent!
俺たち体術使いが
超高速の技に対応できるのは➡
We taijutsu users can
counter supersonic moves
because we have honed
our five senses.
五感を研ぎ澄ますからだ。
その一つに音がある。
One of those senses
is hearing.
そういえば
リーは以前 音忍と戦ったときに➡
I remember…
Lee said he once fought a shinobi
from the Hidden Sound
苦しめられたって言ってたっけ。
who gave him a hard time!
これは あの時と真逆だ。
This time, it's the exact opposite!
シラから まったく音がしない。
Shira is making absolutely no noise!
でも どうして？
But how…?
白眼！
Byakugan!
そうか これはフクロウの原理だ。
I see!
It's the theory of the owl.
フクロウ？
The owl?
フクロウは音を立てずに
飛ぶのを知っているか？
Did you know that owls fly
without making a sound?
翼に特殊な櫛状の羽があって➡
Owls have special
comb-like feathers
それが羽ばたきの音を消す。
that muffle the sound
of their flapping wings.
やつは 体術のみに扱えるチャクラで➡
Using chakra that can only
be used with taijutsu,
全身にその羽を
作り上げているんだ。
he's cloaked himself with
the same type of feathers.
たった一人で
ここまで工夫するとは…。
To come up with something
like that all by himself…
つくづく敵にしておくには
惜しい相手だ。
What a waste to consider
someone like that an enemy.
(リー)うわっ。
無音の拳 受けきれるか！ リー。
Silent Fist!
See if you can take this, Lee!
《うぅ どうすれば…》
How can I…?
((ガイ : 自分を
信じないやつなんかに➡
There's no point in working hard
if you don't believe in yourself!
(努力する価値はない))
《そうです 僕だって➡
Yes! I've trained and worked
just as hard as Shira!
シラ君に負けない
修業をしてきたはずです》
((リー : 999 1,000と。
999…1000!
(ネジ)うわっ。
(テンテン)はぁ。
さぁ これから腹筋 1,000回です。
Now, 1000 sit-ups!
ハァ… マジ？
Are you serious?
マジです！
待て待て待て。
I am serious!
Wait, wait, wait!
ちょっと待て 体力強化は
もう このくらいでいいぞ。
Enough bodybuilding!
体力なら すでに俺たちより➡
You're in far better physical
condition than we are, Lee.
お前のほうが はるかに上だ リー…。
ですが 僕は 一度もガイ先生にも
ネジにも勝ったことはありません。
But Guy Sensei, I've never beaten
you or Neji even once!
あ～ それは お前が
ここを使ってないからだ。
That's because
you don't use this.
体術に頭なんて
関係があるんですか？
Use my head for taijutsu?
あるとも。
Certainly!
頭でイメージすることが
体術の極意といっていい。
It can be said that
mental visualization
is a fundamental part of taijutsu.
俺は 常に組手をするとき➡
When I weave a sign,
I'm already seeing 100 moves ahead.
100手先まで見えている。
え～！
そんなことできるんですか!?
What?! Is such a thing possible?!
できる！ 俺は ひたすら
イメージトレーニングを続けることで➡
Yes, it's possible!
Through visualization alone,
if I'm going to fight Kakashi,
カカシと戦うなら 1,000手先まで
見えるようになった。
I can now see
1000 moves ahead.
そ そんなに!?
Th-That far?
ハッハッハッ… ウッハッハッハッ！
ねえ ほんとなの？
Hey, is that true?
さあな。
Who knows?
仮に俺が右の正拳突きから
攻撃を始めるとする。
For example, if I attack
with a right seiken fist…
リー お前が50手目に
繰り出す技は何だ？
Lee, what would your 50th move be?
え…。
Huh?
お前が50手目に繰り出す技だ。
What technique is your 50th move!
Well…
えっと えっと➡
Let's see…
右手の突きです。
外れ。
A right thrust!
Wrong!
あ… それじゃ 右回し蹴り。
Then… A clockwise kick!
正解。 では 100手目は？
Correct!
So what is your 100th move?!
えっと 左かかと蹴り？
Uh… A left heel kick!
Wrong.
外れ。 正解は 左の回し蹴りだ。
The answer is
a counter-clockwise kick.
は？
What?
今 それを証明してやる。
I will prove it to you right now!
いいか？ フン。
Ready?
うお～！
(ガイ)48 49… 50。
あっ。
48…
49…
50.
あっ。
(ガイ)続けろ。
Continue!
Sensei was right!
先生が言ったことが当たったわ。
98… 99…!
(ガイ)98 99 100。
100!
また当たった。
なるほど。
Right again!
I see…
そうさせているんだ。
えっ？
He's making that happen!
Huh?
(リー)ハァ ハァ ハァ…。
すごいです ガイ先生
どんな手品を？
That's amazing, Guy Sensei!
What's your trick?
手品ではない。
It's not a trick.
I just made you move the way
I wanted you to. That's all.
お前が俺の思うように
動かされていただけの話だ。
あっ 動かされていた？
Made me move?
そうだ お前がそういう動きしか
できないように➡
Yes!
I used counters that forced you
to make certain moves.
俺は 反撃していた。
In battle, there is a sequence
to techniques and jutsu.
技や術の戦いには 流れがある。
When you are in control
of that flow,
それを支配すれば
先を読むことは難しくない。
predicting what comes next
is not difficult.
俺は 今の組手の流れを支配し➡
Right now, I'm controlling
the flow of battle, and as a result,
その結果 俺より体力のあるお前が
先にへばっている。
you, my opponent who's physically
stronger than me,
have lost steam before me!
あっ そうか！
That's true!
ガイ先生は
まったく息が切れていない。
Guy Sensei, you're not
even breathing hard!
流れを支配することで
俺は お前のスタミナを削りながら➡
By controlling the flow of battle,
I was able to deplete your energy
while preserving my own.
体力を温存したのだ。
There really aren't many chances to
take down a foe in the midst of battle.
戦いのなかで
相手を倒すチャンスはそうない。
通常の攻撃は それを生み出す
きっかけに過ぎないのだ。
The usual attack strategy is no more than
an attempt to create such a chance!
(これが頭を使うということだ))
That's what I mean
by using your head!
《そうだ 今までの組手で➡
That's right!
From opponents I've faced before,
I pretty much know Shira's pattern.
シラ君のパターンは
ある程度わかってる。
All I need to do is control the sequence
of my opponent's moves.
だったら この組手の流れを
支配するんだ。
そうすれば 音は聞こえなくても➡
Then, even if his moves are silent,
I can anticipate Shira's fist!
シラ君の攻撃を予測できます》
よし！
なに!?
All right!
What?!
リーに攻撃が当たらなくなった。
Lee's not getting hit anymore!
リーのやつ やっとあの時の修業を
思い出したか。
Finally, Lee…
You remembered that training!
He's countering so fast!
《対応が早い。 ますます
キミの本気を見たくなったよ》
I can't wait to see when
he's giving it his all!
うぅっ！
He missed the Chakra Point!
《点穴が外れてる！
どういうことだ？
偶然 外れたのか？》
What's going on?
Was it by chance?
《ガイ先生は いきなり
六門から発動できる。
At this point…
Guy Sensei would be able to activate
the Sixth Gate instantly…
That's impossible for me, however…
そこまでは無理でも…》
はぁ～！ 第三生門！ 開！
The Third Gate of Life! Open!
いきなり第三門から…
リーのやつ そこまでの修業を。
He went straight to
the Third Gate…
So Lee's trained that far!
それが噂に聞く 八門遁甲…
ならば！
So that's the rumored
Eight Inner Gates...
Well then…
はぁ～！ 七天呼法 第一活性！
Seven Heavenly Breaths!
First Activation!
第二活性！
Second Activation!
第三活性！
Third Activation!
何だ!? あれは。
What is that?!
あれは シラが編み出した
呼吸法による体術です。
It's a taijutsu breathing method
that Shira came up with.
酸素を多く取り込むことで
全身を活性化させる術よ。
It's a jutsu whereby inhaling
large amounts of oxygen
invigorates the entire body.
シラは あの技をやるとき 肺活量が
通常の４倍近くになるわ。
When performing this technique,
Shira's lung capacity increases
nearly fourfold.
独自の八門遁甲というわけか。
So it's his version of
the Eight Inner Gates.
It's amazing that he came up
with that all by himself…
すごい そんなものまで一人で。
まったく あの２人には
思い知らされる。
Those two really drive home the fact…
努力には限界がないということを。
that there is no limit
to perseverance.
ほんとだわ。 リー！ シラ！
どっちも頑張れ！
No kidding!
Lee! Shira!
Do your best, both of you!
いきますよ シラ君！
Here I come, Shira!
来い！
Anytime!
Not yet!
まだです！ 第四傷門 開！
Fourth Gate of Pain! Open!
第五杜門 開！
Fifth Gate of Closing! Open!
うぉ～！
《これがお前の本気か。
So this is what you're like
when you're serious!
俺のチャクラが… 音なしの羽が
吹き飛ばされていく！》
My chakra…my sound-muffling feathers
are being blown away!
I'm starting to hear…
the sound of your wings.
聞こえてきましたよ
キミのこぶしの音が！
うっ！
Leaf Hurricane!
木ノ葉旋風！
うわっ！
まだまだだ。
I'm not done yet…
Shira's wound has opened up!
傷口が開いたんです！ シラ！
Shira!
シラ君！
大丈夫ですか？ シラ君。
Are you okay, Shira?!
ああ。
Yeah…
どうやらこの勝負
お預けのようですね。
I guess we'll have to
postpone this match.
Lee, I envy you.
リー キミがうらやましいよ。
俺もガイ先生に
一度 教えを受けてみたかった。
I wish I could have trained under
Guy Sensei at least once.
シラ君 どうして僕の点穴を
解除したんですか？
Shira… Why did you release
my Chakra Points?
気づいたのか。
So you noticed?
どうしても
キミの全力と戦ってみたかった。
I wanted to fight you
when you could give
a hundred percent.
思ったとおり キミは強かった。
As I expected, you are strong.
(シラ)いい経験をさせてもらったよ。
It was a great experience.
(セン)何 バカ言ってんの！
What are you saying?
You were too reckless!
(ヨメ)無茶するからです！
Shira, I want you to have this.
シラ君 キミにこれをあげます。
Guy Sensei gave it to me.
これは ガイ先生から
もらったものです。
This is what made me strong.
僕は これで強くなりました。
It is a unique item with
superior breathability
通気性 保湿性に優れ
動きやすさを追求しつくした逸品。
and moisture-wicking qualities
that lets you move easily!
修業のときに着ると
その違いが すぐにわかる！
You'll see the difference
when you train!
すぐ クセになる！
これを着れば 僕たちは➡
You'll get attached
to it immediately!
Wear this…
and we'll be brothers!
兄弟です！
ありがとう もらっておくよ。
Thanks… I accept it.
シラ君 さっき 最後になると
言ってましたが。
Shira… You said earlier
that this is the last time…
風の国には 北の国境を警備する
部隊があってな。
In the Land of Wind,
there is a battalion that guards
the northern border.
どんなときでも
その部隊は 任務地を離れない。
That battalion never leaves
its station.
そこは 過酷な環境ゆえ
志願者が ほとんどいないんだ。
The environment there
is extremely harsh,
so few candidates
are willing to accept that mission.
だが俺は この試験に合格したら
そこに志願しようと思う。
I plan to volunteer for it
if I pass these Exams.
えっ…。
故郷が近くでな。
It's near my hometown.
病気の両親の近くにいてやりたい。
My parents are sick and
I want to be close to them.
だから もう キミたちに
会うことも二度とないだろう。
So I probably won't see
any of you again.
そうだったんですね。
シラ そんなつもりだったんだ。
I see how it is...
Shira… I had no idea.
でも それじゃ もう
ヨメとは会えないんだね。
I guess that means I won't
be seeing you around either, Yome.
あんた どうせ
シラに くっついてくんだろ？
You're probably going
to tag along, right?
えっ えっ!?
俺は 自分の人生を
後悔してはいない。
I have no regrets with my life.
だが もし
キミのような友がいたなら➡
But I'm sure my life would
have been more interesting
きっと楽しい人生を送れると思う。
if I had had a friend like you.
キミからの最高の褒め言葉だと
受け取っておきます！
I'm going to remember that as
the greatest compliment from you!
最高の褒め言葉のつもりだ。 リー！
And I mean it as such, Lee,
in all sincerity.
(リー)巻物も 二本 揃いましたし！
Now we have two scrolls!
Then let's head straight
for home base!
(テンテン)あとは ゴール地点に
まっしぐらね！
HEAVEN      HEAVEN
さて いつ話すかな？
So, when should I break
the news to them...?
調査班の報告によると
滝隠れのフウの班ですが➡
FUU TOCCHI KUN
According to reports from
the investigative team,
FUU TOCCHI KUN
two members of Team Fuu
from the Hidden Waterfall…
トッチと クンと名乗る２人は
実際には 下忍ではなく➡
FUU TOCCHI KUN
Tocchi and Kun…
are actually not genin.
ケゴンと ヨウロウという名の
上忍だと思われます。
It is believed they are jonin
named Kegon and Yoro.
Damn Hidden Waterfall…
滝隠れめ 何を企んでいるのか。
What are they scheming?
待て。
Wait.
この件に関しては 俺が預かる。
Let me handle this.
(２人)は？
この事実は➡
This information is not
to go out of this room.
我々の間だけにとどめる。
(２人)しかし！
– But!
The Second Exam will
continue uninterrupted.
二次試験は
つつがなく継続される。
いいな。
Understood?!
What is Lord Gaara thinking?!
いったい
何を考えておられるのか。
It will be sundown soon.
(ケゴン)もうすぐ 日が暮れる。
(ヨウロウ)そうだな。
Yes.
From here, we'll be able to sense
the enemy's presence right away.
ここなら 近づく敵も
いち早く察知できる。
It's the perfect spot to make camp.
野宿には 最適だ。
(ケゴン)で フウは？
So where's Fuu?
Hey! She was over there
just a second ago…
(ヨウロウ)あれ？ 今さっきまで
そこいらに…。
Fuu!
フウ！
That b
ったく！ 勝手気ままに！
あっ… なんだ？
(フウ)ツンツン。
(ヨウロウ)
フウ！ 勝手にうろつき回るな！
(ケゴン)まったく！
他の里の者の奇襲を➡
受けたら どうするつもりだ！
フウは 滝隠れにとって重要な…。
わかった！ 今 行くっす！
やれやれ。 そんな騒いだら
見つかっちゃうっすよ。
フウ…。
あいつは…。
豆助 きょうは今が旬の
あれを使った小鉢よ
< その小鉢とは？>